W
We
We A
We Ar
We Are
We Are F
We Are Fa
We Are Fam
We Are Fami
We Are Famil
We Are Family
Team WAF
Sub2smi by
WAF-CAP 블랙이글
매트릭스
(The Matrix, 1999)
네?
- Is everything in place?
- You're not to relieve me.
- 전부 준비됐나?
- 너랑 교대하는 건 아니잖아
알지만 하고 싶었어
I know, but I felt like taking a shift.
그 자를 좋아하지?
지켜보는 걸 좋아하지
- You like him, don't you?
- You like watching him.
- 말도 안 돼
- 우린 그를 죽일 거야
- Don't be ridiculous.
- We're going to kill him.
Morpheus believes he is the One.
모피어스는 그가 맞다고 믿어
Do you?
- 너도?
- 난 상관 안 해
It doesn't matter what I believe.
안 믿지?
You don't, do you?
- 방금 들었어?
- 뭘?
- Did you hear that?
- Hear what?
도청되는 거 아냐?
Are you sure this line is clean?
Yeah, of course I'm sure.
그럴리 없어
I better go.
가야겠어
- 꼼짝 마!
- 손들어!
- Freeze! Police!
- Hands on your head!
지금 당장! 당장!
Do it! Do it now!
'하트 오브 더 시티 호텔'
- Lieutenant.
- Oh, shit.
- 경위
- 젠장
Lieutenant, you were given
specific orders.
그냥 지키기만 하랬잖소
내 임무를 수행했을 뿐이오
I'm just doing my job.
관할 구역 어쩌고저쩌고
따위의 말은 집어치우쇼
You give me that "juris-my-dick-tion"
crap, you can cram it up your ass.
The orders were for your protection.
댁의 안전을 위한 조치였소
I think we can handle one little girl.
그깟 계집애 하나 때문에?
두 팀을 보냈으니
I sent two units!
곧 잡아 올 거요
They're bringing her down now!
아니, 당신 부하들은
벌써 죽었소
No, lieutenant, your men
are already dead.
Shit.
젠장
모피어스, 추적당했어요
Morpheus, the line was traced.
I don't know how.
놈들이 선을 잘랐어
I know. They cut the hard line.
시간이 없어, 출구를 찾아
There's no time.
Get to another exit.
- 요원들이 있어요?
- 그래
- Are there any agents?
- Yes.
빌어먹을
Goddamn it.
정신을 집중해, 트리니티
You have to focus, Trinity.
웰스가와 레이크가에
공중전화가 있다
There's a phone at Wells and Lake.
You can make it.
넌 할 수 있어
- 알았어요
- 가!
- All right.
- Go.
저건 말도 안 돼
That's impossible.
일어나, 트리니티
Get up, Trinity. Just get up.
일어나!
Get up.
빠져나갔군
She got out.
It doesn't matter.
상관없어
정보가 확실했군
- The informant is real.
- Yes.
- 다음 표적을 알아
- 바로 네오지
We have the name of their next target.
The name is Neo.
자료를 검색해야겠군
We'll need a search running.
이미 시작했어
It has already begun.
'검색 중...'
'히드로 공항에서
모피어스가 경찰을 따돌림'
'범인 추적 중'
'일어나, 네오...'
뭐야?
What?
'넌 매트릭스한테 잡혔다'
What the hell?
뭔 소리지?
'흰 토끼를 쫓아라'
"Follow the white rabbit."
흰 토끼를 쫓으라고?
'똑똑, 네오'
누구세요?
Who is it?
초이야
It's Choi.
Yeah. Yeah.
2시간이나 늦었어
You're two hours late.
I know. It's her fault.
- 알아, 얘 탓이야
- 돈은?
You got the money?
2천 달러
Two grand.
기다려
Hold on.
'시뮬라크라와 시뮬라시옹'
할렐루야!
Hallelujah.
You're my savior.
My own personal Jesus Christ.
넌 내 구세주야
만약 걸리면...
You get caught using that...
알아, 난 널 모르는 거지
I know. This never happened.
You don't exist.
- 그래
- 무슨 일 있어?
- Right.
- Something wrong, man?
유난히 창백해 보여
You look a little whiter than usual.
내 컴퓨터가...
My computer, it...
꿈인지 생시인지
분간이 안 갈 때 있어?
Ever have that feeling where you're
not sure if you're awake or dreaming?
All the time.
It's called mescaline.
항상 그래
메스칼린 때문이지
It's the only way to fly.
진짜 죽여줘
컴퓨터 좀 어지간히 해라
It just sounds like you
need to unplug.
너도 좀 쉬어야지
Get some R and R?
어때, 두즈어?
데리고 갈까?
What do you think, Dujour?
Should we take him with us?
당연하지
Definitely.
안 돼, 내일도 일해야 돼
No, I can't. I have work tomorrow.
가자
Come on.
재미있을 거야, 진짜로
It'll be fun. I promise.
좋아
Yeah.
Sure. I'll go.
가지 뭐
Hello, Neo.
안녕, 네오
How do you know that name?
날 어떻게 알지?
난 널 잘 알아
I know a lot about you.
- Who are you?
- My name is Trinity.
- 누구지?
- 난 트리니티야
트리니티
Trinity.
The Trinity?
그 트리니티?
국세청을 해킹했던?
That cracked the IRS D-base?
오래 전 얘기지
That was a long time ago.
- Jesus.
- What?
- 맙소사
- 왜?
당신이...
I just thought...
...you were a guy.
- 남자인 줄 알았거든
- 다들 그래
Most guys do.
That was you on my computer.
나한테 메시지를 보냈지?
How did you do that?
- 어떻게 한 거야?
- 중요한 건...
Right now, all I can tell you...
넌 지금 위험하다는 거야
...is that you're in danger.
- 경고하려고 불렀어
- 무슨 경고?
- I brought you here to warn you.
- Of what?
그들이 널 보고 있어
They're watching you, Neo.
- Who is?
- Please just listen.
- 누가?
- 그냥 듣기만 해
네가 왜 여기 왔는지 알아
I know why you're here, Neo.
네가 뭘 했으며
I know what you've been doing.
I know why you hardly sleep...
왜 잠을 못 자고
...why you live alone and why,
night after night...
혼자 살며 밤이면 밤마다
왜 컴퓨터 앞에 앉는지도
...you sit at your computer.
넌 그를 찾고 있어
You're looking for him.
난 알아, 나도 한때
그랬으니까
I know, because I was once
looking for the same thing.
And when he found me...
그가 날 찾았을 때...
그는 내가 찾던 건
자기가 아니라...
...he told me I wasn't really
looking for him...
해답이랬어
...I was looking for an answer.
우릴 움직이는 건 질문이지
It's the question that drives us, Neo.
그게 널 여기까지
오게 만든 거야
It's the question
that brought you here.
You know the question...
넌 그 질문이...
...just as I did.
뭔지 알아
매트릭스란 뭔가?
What is the Matrix?
정답은 어딘가에 있어
The answer is out there, Neo.
그것은 널 찾고 있고
It's looking for you.
And it will find you...
곧 찾을 거야
네가 원한다면
...if you want it to.
젠장...
Shit.
젠장!
Shit, shit.
자넨 법에 불만이 있나 보군
You have a problem with authority,
Mr. Anderson.
자신이 법을 어겨도 되는
특별한 존재인 줄 아나?
You believe that you are special,
that the rules do not apply to you.
잘못 생각했네
Obviously, you are mistaken.
우리는 세계 최고의
소프트웨어 회사지
This is one of the top
software companies in the world...
직원들이 똘똘 뭉쳐
일궈낸 결과야
...because employees understand
they are part of a whole.
고로 직원의 문제는
곧 회사의 문제지
Thus, if an employee has a problem,
the company has a problem.
The time has come to make
a choice, Mr. Anderson.
이제 자네가 결정하게, 앤더슨
Either you choose to be at your desk
on time from this day forth...
오늘부터 제 시간에
출근을 하든가
...or you choose to find another job.
아니면 다른 직장을
알아보든가
알아듣겠나?
Do I make myself clear?
잘 알겠습니다
Yes, Mr. Rhineheart.
Perfectly clear.
Thomas Anderson?
토마스 앤더슨 씨?
전데요
Yeah, that's me.
Okay.
고마워요
Great.
안녕히 계세요
Have a nice day.
Hello?
- 여보세요?
- 네오!
Hello, Neo. Do you know who this is?
내가 누군지 알지?
- 모피어스?
- 그래
- Morpheus.
- Yes.
그동안 널 찾았다
I've been looking for you.
내가 보여주려는 걸
볼 준비가 됐는지 모르겠군
I don't know if you're ready to see
what I want to show you.
한데 불행히도 시간이 없어
But unfortunately, you and I
have run out of time.
그들이 곧 갈 거다
무슨 짓을 할지는 몰라
They're coming for you, and I don't know
what they're going to do.
누가 오는데요?
Who's coming for me?
일어나서 네가 직접 봐
Stand up and see for yourself.
지금요?
What? Right now?
그래, 지금
Yes. Now.
천천히
Do it slowly.
승강기 쪽을 봐
The elevator.
- Oh, shit!
- Yes.
- 젠장!
- 그래
What do they want?
- 저들이 왜 날 찾죠?
- 나도 몰라
I don't know. If you don't want
to find out, get out of there.
일단은 튀는 게 상책이야
How?
- 어떻게?
- 도와주지
I can guide you,
but you must do exactly as I say.
내 지시대로 해야 돼
- Okay.
- The cubicle across from you is empty.
- 좋아요
- 옆칸이 비어있다
- 만약 그들이...
- 빨리 가!
- But what if they--
- Go. Now.
Stay here for just a moment.
잠깐만 거기 있어
When I tell you,
go to the end of the row...
내가 지시하면 복도 맨 끝의
사무실로 가
...to the office
at the end of the hall.
최대한 몸을 숙이고
Stay as low as you can.
지금 가!
Go. Now.
Good. Now, outside
there is a scaffold.
좋아, 밖에 비계가 있다
- 어떻게 알았죠?
- 시간이 없다
- How do you know this?
- We don't have time.
왼쪽 창문으로 가
To your left there's a window.
Go to it.
열어
Open it.
비계를 타고 옥상으로 가
Take the scaffold to the roof.
말도 안 돼!
이건 미친 짓이야!
No way! No way!
This is crazy!
나갈 방법은 두 가지다
There are two ways
out of this building.
비계를 이용하든가
놈들한테 잡히든가
One is that scaffold.
The other is in their custody.
You take a chance either way.
I leave it to you.
선택은 네 맘이야
This is insane!
미친 짓이야!
Why is this happening to me?
이게 다 뭐야?
What'd I do?
내가 뭘 어쨌길래?
I'm nobody.
I didn't do anything.
난 아무 짓도 안 했어
I'm gonna die.
죽겠군
젠장
Shit!
젠장!
Oh, shit!
I can't do this.
난 못 해
Shit.
젠장
As you can see, we've had our eye on
you for some time now, Mr. Anderson.
보다시피 우린 한동안
자넬 지켜봐 왔다, 앤더슨
It seems that you've been living...
두 개의 인생을
살고 있더군
...two lives.
하나는 소프트웨어 회사의
In one life,
you're Thomas A. Anderson...
프로그래머인 토마스 앤더슨
...program writer for
a respectable software company.
You have a social security number.
You pay your taxes.
떳떳한 시민으로서
세금도 내고
그리고...
And you...
집주인 아줌마의
쓰레기도 버려 주지
...help your landlady
carry out her garbage.
다른 하나는
The other life is lived in computers...
'네오'라는 이름의 해커로서
...where you go by
the hacker alias "Neo"...
온갖 컴퓨터 범죄는
죄다 저질렀더군
...and are guilty of virtually every
computer crime we have a law for.
One of these lives...
두 삶 중 하나는
앞날이 보장돼 있고
...has a future.
다른 하나는 미래가 없어
And one of them does not.
아주 솔직하게 털어놓겠네
I'm going to be as forthcoming
as I can be, Mr. Anderson.
You're here...
우린
...because we need your help.
자네의 도움이 필요해
어떤 자가...
We know that you've been contacted
by a certain...
...individual.
연락해 왔지?
'모피어스'라는 자 말이야
A man who calls himself "Morpheus."
그에 대해 자네가 아는 건
전부 무시해
Whatever you think you know
about this man is irrelevant.
정부에서도 그자를
He is considered by many authorities...
...to be the most dangerous man alive.
가장 위험한 인물로 찍었으니
내 동료들은
My colleagues...
내가 자네 일로
시간 낭비를 한다고 봐
...believe that I am wasting
my time with you.
하지만 난 자넬 믿네
But I believe you wish
to do the right thing.
자네가 새 출발을 하게
We're willing to wipe the slate clean...
도와줄 수도 있어
...give you a fresh start.
All we're asking in return
is your cooperation...
자넨 테러범 체포를
도와주기만 하면 돼
...in bringing
a known terrorist to justice.
네
Yeah.
귀가 솔깃하네요
That sounds like a really good deal.
더 좋은 게 있는데...
But I got a better one.
당신은
How about...
...I give you the finger...
이거나 먹고
...and you give me my phone call.
내가 전화나 하게 해주시죠
Mr. Anderson...
이런, 앤더슨...
날 실망시키는군
...you disappoint me.
You can't scare me
with this gestapo crap.
그런다고 겁낼 줄 알아?
난 내 권리를 알아
I know my rights.
전화하게 해줘
I want my phone call.
Tell me, Mr. Anderson...
얘기도 못 할 텐데...
전화가 무슨 소용이지?
...what good is a phone call...
...if you're unable to speak?
좋든 싫든 간에
You're going to help us,
Mr. Anderson...
...whether you want to or not.
넌 우릴 도와야 할 걸
도청 당하고 있으니까
짧게 하지
This line is tapped,
so I must be brief.
놈들이 먼저 널 잡았지만
널 과소평가했어
They got to you first, but they've
underestimated how important you are.
If they knew what I know...
내가 아는 걸
그들이 알았다면
넌 죽었을 거야
...you would probably be dead.
What are you talking about?
What is happening to me?
무슨 소리예요?
어찌 된 일이죠?
네가 바로 '그'야, 네오
넌 수년간 날 찾았겠지만
You are the One, Neo. You may have
spent the last few years...
난 평생을...
...Iooking for me, but I've spent
my entire life...
널 찾아다녔어
...Iooking for you.
아직도 날 만나고 싶나?
Now, do you still want to meet?
- Yes.
- Then go to the Adams Street bridge.
- 그래요
- 그럼 아담스가 다리로 와
타
Get in.
What's this?
- 왜 이래?
- 필요하니까
It's necessary, Neo.
For our protection.
- 안전을 위해서야
- 뭣 때문에?
- From what?
- From you.
너 때문이야
- 셔츠를 벗어
- 뭐?
- Take off your shirt.
- What?
Stop the car.
차를 세워
내 말 잘 들어
Listen, coppertop.
스무고개 할 시간 없어
We don't have time for 20 Questions.
Right now, there's only one rule:
시키는 대로 하든가
아니면
Our way...
나가든가
...or the highway.
Fine.
좋아
네오, 날 믿어야 해
Please, Neo, you have to trust me.
- 왜?
- 다 겪어봐서 알잖아
- Why?
- Because you have been down there.
나가면 결과가
You know that road.
어떻게 될지 말이야
You know exactly where it ends.
그건 네가 바라는 게 아냐
And I know that's
not where you want to be.
에이팍, 조명
Apoc, lights.
- Lie back.
- Lift up your shirt.
누워서 셔츠를 올려
- What's that?
- You're bugged.
- 뭘 하게?
- 벌레가 있어
Try and relax.
긴장을 풀어
어디 있어?
Come on.
나와 봐
It's on the move.
움직이고 있어
젠장
Come on, you shit.
- 놓치겠어
- 걱정 마
- You're gonna lose it.
- No, I'm not.
Clear!
준비...
맙소사, 진짜였어?
Jesus Christ!
That thing's real!?
This is it.
여기야
Let me give you one piece of advice.
충고 한마디 하지
Be honest.
정직해야 돼
He knows more than you can imagine.
그를 과소평가하지 마
At last.
결국 왔군
잘 왔네, 네오
Welcome, Neo.
짐작했겠지만
As you no doubt have guessed...
...I am Morpheus.
내가 모피어스다
영광입니다
It's an honor to meet you.
아니
No...
내가 영광이네
...the honor is mine.
거기 앉게나
Please, come. Sit.
I imagine...
지금 자넨
이상한 나라의
앨리스가 된 기분이겠지?
...that right now you're feeling
a bit like Alice...
...tumbling down the rabbit hole?
토끼 구멍으로
떨어진 것 같지?
You could say that.
그런 것 같아요
얼굴에 쓰여 있어
I can see it in your eyes.
You have the look of a man
who accepts what he sees...
자넨 곧 꿈에서
깨어날 걸 알기에
눈에 보이는 대로
믿는 사람 같군
...because he's expecting to wake up.
Ironically, this is not
far from the truth.
실제로 자넨 곧 깨어날 거야
Do you believe in fate, Neo?
운명을 믿나, 네오?
No.
- 아뇨
- 왜지?
Why not?
I don't like the idea that
I'm not in control of my life.
나 자신의 삶을
통제할 수 없으니까요
무슨 뜻인지 알아
I know exactly what you mean.
Let me tell you why you're here.
네가 온 이유를 말해 주지
뭔가를 알기 때문에 온 거야
그게 뭔지 설명은 못 해
You know something.
What you know,
you can't explain.
하지만 느껴져
But you feel it.
평생을 느껴 왔어
You felt it your entire life:
Something's wrong with the world.
You don't know what, but it's there.
뭔지는 모르지만 세상이
잘못됐다는 걸 말이야
머리가 깨질 것처럼
Like a splinter in your mind...
자넬 미치게 만들지
...driving you mad.
그 느낌에 이끌려 온 거야
It is this feeling
that has brought you to me.
무슨 말인지 알겠나?
Do you know what
I'm talking about?
The Matrix?
매트릭스요?
그게 뭔지
Do you want to know...
알고 싶나?
...what it is?
The Matrix is everywhere.
매트릭스는 모든 곳에 있어
우리 주위의 모든 곳에
It is all around us.
바로 이 방안에도 있고
Even now, in this very room.
창밖을 내다봐도 있고
You can see it when you
look out your window...
...or when you turn on your television.
TV 안에도 있지
출근할 때도 느껴지고
You can feel it when you go to work...
교회에 갈 때도
...when you go to church...
세금을 낼 때도
...when you pay your taxes.
진실을 못 보도록
눈을 가리는
It is the world that has been
pulled over your eyes...
세계란 말이지
...to blind you from the truth.
무슨 진실요?
What truth?
네가 노예란 진실
That you are a slave.
너도 다른 사람과 마찬가지로
Like everyone else,
you were born into bondage...
...born into a prison that you cannot
smell or taste or touch.
모든 감각이 마비된 채
감옥에서 태어났지
A prison...
네 마음의 감옥
...for your mind.
불행히도 매트릭스가 뭔지
Unfortunately, no one can be...
말로는 설명할 수 없어
...told what the Matrix is.
You have to see it for yourself.
직접 봐야만 해
This is your last chance.
이게 마지막 기회다
다시는 돌이킬 수 없어
After this, there is no turning back.
You take the blue pill...
파란 약을 먹으면
여기서 끝난다
침대에서 깨어나
...the story ends, you wake up
in your bed and believe...
네가 믿고 싶은 걸 믿게 돼
...whatever you want to believe.
빨간 약을 먹으면
You take the red pill...
이상한 나라에 남아
...you stay in Wonderland...
...and I show you how deep
the rabbit hole goes.
끝까지 가게 된다
명심해
Remember...
난 진실만을 제안한다
...all I'm offering is the truth.
Nothing more.
Follow me.
날 따라와
에이팍, 연결됐나?
Apoc, are we on-line?
거의 다 됐어요
Almost.
Time is always against us.
항상 시간에 쫓기지
Please take a seat there.
자리에 앉아
- You did all this?
Mm-hm.
- 다 당신이 한 거야?
- 그래
The pill you took is
part of a trace program.
알약은 추적을 위한 거다
It disrupts your carrier signals
so we can pinpoint your location.
반송 신호를 교란시켜
자네의 위치를 파악하지
무슨 뜻이죠?
What does that mean?
꽉 붙잡으란 얘기야
It means buckle your
seat belt, Dorothy...
곧 깜짝 놀라게 될 테니까
...because Kansas...
...is going bye-bye.
당신이?
Did you...?
진짜 현실 같은 꿈을
꿔 본 적 있나?
Have you ever had a dream, Neo,
that you were so sure was real?
What if you were unable
to wake from that dream?
그런 꿈에서
깨어날 수 없다면?
그것이 꿈인지 생시인지
How would you know the difference
between the dream world...
...and the real world?
어떻게 알 수 있지?
This can't be.
- 이건 불가능해
- 뭐가?
Be what?
진짜란 게?
Be real?
- Going into replication.
- Apoc?
- 복제하고 있어요
- 에이팍?
Still nothing.
아직 안 돼요
It's cold.
추워요... 추워...
It's cold!
탱크, 신호가 필요해
Tank, we'll need a signal soon.
심장이 세동합니다
- I got a fibrillation.
- Apoc, location.
에이팍, 위치는?
거의 찾았어
Targeting almost there.
He's going into arrest.
심장이 곧 멎어요
- 찾았어요
- 지금이야, 탱크!
- Lock. I got him!
- Now, Tank, now!
여기가
Welcome...
...to the real world.
진짜 세상이다
We've done it, Trinity.
우린...
'그'를 찾은 거야
We found him.
- 당신이 맞길 바래요
- 확실하다니까
- I hope you're right.
- I don't have to hope.
확실해
I know it.
내가 죽었나요?
Am I dead?
정반대지
Far from it.
손을 많이 봐야 해요
He still needs a lot of work.
뭐 하는 거죠?
What are you doing?
근위축증이야
Your muscles atrophied.
We're rebuilding them.
Why do my eyes hurt?
눈은 왜 아프죠?
사용한 적이 없으니까
You've never used them before.
Rest, Neo.
편히 쉬어, 네오
답은 곧 온다
The answers are coming.
Morpheus, what's happened to me?
모피어스, 어떻게 된 거죠?
What is this place?
- 여긴 어디예요?
- 그보다는 언제냐가 중요해
More important than "what" is "when."
"When"?
- 언제죠?
- 1999년인 줄 알겠지만
You believe it's the year 1999...
사실은 2199년에 가까워
...when in fact, it's closer to 2199.
정확한 연도는 나도 잘 몰라
I can't tell you exactly
what year it is...
...because we honestly don't know.
말로는 설명이 안 되네
There's nothing I can say
that will explain it for you.
Come with me.
See for yourself.
자네가 직접 보라구
여긴...
This is my ship.
The Nebuchadnezzar.
It's a hovercraft.
느부갓네살호다
나의 호버크래프트지
여긴 주갑판이고
This is the main deck.
This is the core...
여기가 심장부야
'느부갓네살
제조 : 미국, 2069년'
...where we broadcast our pirate signal
and hack into the Matrix.
매트릭스에 해킹하기 위해
해적 신호를 보내지
Most of my crew you already know.
내 대원들은 거의 다 알지?
This is Apoc...
여긴 에이팍
스위치
...Switch...
- 그리고 사이퍼
- 안녕
- ...and Cypher.
- Hi.
이들은 초면이지?
탱크와 그의 형 도저
The ones you don't know:
Tank and his big brother, Dozer.
뒤의 작은 친구는 마우스다
The little one behind you is Mouse.
You wanted to know
what the Matrix is?
매트릭스가 뭔지 궁금한가?
트리니티
Trinity.
Try to relax.
긴장 풀어
기분이 이상할 거야
This will feel a little weird.
'보조 드라이브'
This...
이게
...is the Construct.
'컨스트럭트'다
It's our loading program.
로딩 프로그램이지
뭐든지 로드할 수 있어
옷이든...
We can load anything, from clothing...
...to equipment...
장비든
...weapons...
무기든...
훈련 시뮬레이션이든
...training simulations...
...anything we need.
필요한 건 전부 다
Right now we're inside
a computer program?
프로그램 안이라구요?
그렇게 믿기가 힘든가?
Is it really so hard to believe?
자네 옷도 바뀌었고
머리와 몸의 구멍도 없어
Your clothes are different.
The plugs in your body are gone.
머리 모양도 다르고
Your hair has changed.
Your appearance now is what we call
"residual self-image."
지금 자네의 모습은
'잉여 자기 이미지'란 거야
It is the mental projection
of your digital self.
자신이 생각하는 모습을
디지털화한 거지
This isn't real?
- 진짜가 아닌가요?
- 진짜가 뭔데?
What is "real"?
How do you define "real"?
정의를 어떻게 내려?
촉각이나 후각, 미각
시각을 뜻하는 거라면
If you're talking about
what you can feel...
...what you can smell, taste and see...
'진짜'란 두뇌가 해석하는
전자 신호에 불과해
...then "real" is simply electrical
signals interpreted by your brain.
This is the world that you know.
이게 자네가 아는 세상이야
The world as it was at the end
of the 20th century.
바로 20세기 말의 모습이지
이젠 매트릭스라는
신경 상호작용 시뮬레이션의
It exists now only as part of
a neural-interactive simulation...
...that we call the Matrix.
일부로만 존재하지
자넨 꿈나라에서 살았었네
You've been living
in a dream world, Neo.
이 세계가 오늘날의 세계야
This is the world...
...as it exists today.
Welcome to "the desert...
여기가 진실의...
사막이네
...of the real."
우리도 확실히는 모르지만
We have only bits and pieces
of information.
한 가지 확실한 건
인류는 21세기 초의
But what we know for certain
is that in the early 21 st century...
어느 시점엔가
스스로 경탄하며
...all of mankind was united
in celebration.
Al의 탄생을 한마음으로
축하했다는 거야
We marveled at our own magnificence
as we gave birth to AI.
Al라면...
AI.
인공지능?
You mean artificial intelligence.
기계들의 일족을 생산해낸
단일 자의식이었지
A singular consciousness that spawned
an entire race of machines.
We don't know who struck first,
us or them.
우리와 그들 중 누가
먼저 공격 했는진 몰라
다만 인류가 하늘을
불태운 건 확실해
But we know that it was us
that scorched the sky.
They were dependent on solar power...
당시의 기계들은
태양력에 의존했고
에너지의 원천인
태양이 없으면
...and it was believed that
they would be unable to survive...
...without an energy source
as abundant as the sun.
그들은 멸망할 거라고 믿었지
인류는 생존을 위해
기계에 의존해 왔어
Throughout human history, we have
been dependent on machines to survive.
Fate, it seems, is not
without a sense of irony.
운명이란
모순적일 때가 많아
The human body generates more
bioelectricity than a 120-volt battery.
인체는 120볼트 건전지
이상의 전기를 발생하고
체열은 2만 5천 BTU가 넘어
And over 25,000 BTUs of body heat.
기계들은 핵융합과 결합하여
Combined with a form of fusion...
필요한 에너지를 다 얻었지
...the machines had found all the energy
they would ever need.
There are fields, Neo,
endless fields...
끝도 없이 널린
벌판이야, 네오
...where human beings
are no longer born.
인간은 태어나는 게 아니라
재배되는 거지
We are grown.
나도 오랫동안 믿지 못 했어
For the longest time,
I wouldn't believe it.
그러다가 직접 본 거야
And then I saw the fields
with my own eyes...
죽은 자를 액화시켜
...watched them liquefy the dead...
...so they could be fed intravenously
to the living.
산 자에게 주입하는 걸
And standing there,
facing the pure, horrifying precision...
끔찍하리만치 정확한
기계들을 보면서
난 명백한 진실을 깨달았지
...I came to realize
the obviousness of the truth.
매트릭스가 뭐지?
What is the Matrix?
통제야
Control.
매트릭스는 컴퓨터가 만든
꿈의 세계야
The Matrix is a computer-generated
dream world...
우릴 통제하기 위한 거지
...built to keep us under control...
인간을 이것으로...
...in order to change a human being...
만들려고
...into this.
아냐!
No.
I don't believe it.
믿을 수 없어
불가능해
It's not possible.
믿기 쉽다고는 안 했어
I didn't say it would be easy, Neo.
I just said it would be the truth.
- 진실이라고만 했지
- 그만 해!
Stop!
나가고 싶어!
Let me out!
Let me out! I want out!
나가게 해 줘!
- Easy, Neo. Easy.
- Get this thing out of me.
- 진정해, 네오
- 빨리 뽑아!
뽑아 버려...
Get this thing out of me!
날 만지지 마, 저리 가!
Don't touch me!
Stay away from me!
I don't believe it.
난 안 믿어!
안 믿는다구!
I don't believe it.
- 안 믿어
- 미쳐 가요
- He's gonna pop.
- Breathe, Neo.
숨을 쉬어, 어서!
Just breathe.
I can't go back, can I?
다시 돌아갈 순 없죠?
그래
No.
돌아갈 수 있다면
But if you could...
가겠나?
...would you really want to?
사과를 해야겠군
규칙이 있지
I owe you an apology.
We have a rule.
We never free a mind
once it's reached a certain age.
일정한 나이가 될 때까진
이 얘길 안 해
It's dangerous.
위험하니까
The mind has trouble letting go.
받아들이질 못 하거든
I've seen it before, and I'm sorry.
그런 경우를 봤어, 미안해
하지만 난 해야 할 일을
I did what I did because...
...I had to.
한 거야
When the Matrix was first built,
there was a man born inside...
매트릭스가 건설될 때
안에서 태어난 자가 있었지
그는 원하는 바를
바꿀 수 있는 능력이 있었어
...who had the ability
to change whatever he wanted...
...to remake the Matrix as he saw fit.
매트릭스를 보기에
합당하게 바꿀 수 있었지
그가 최초로
우리들을 풀어주고
It was he who freed the first of us...
...taught us the truth.
진실을 가르쳤지
As long as the Matrix exists...
매트릭스가 존재하는 한
인류는 자유를 얻지 못 해
...the human race will never be free.
그가 죽은 후...
After he died...
...the Oracle prophesied his return...
오라클은 그의 재림을
예언했지
그가 매트릭스를 파멸시키고
...and that his coming would hail
the destruction of the Matrix...
전쟁을 종식시킴으로써
...end the war...
인류를 구원할 거라고
...bring freedom to our people.
그래서 우린 평생 동안
매트릭스에서
That is why there are those of us who
spent our lives searching the Matrix...
그를 찾았지
...Iooking for him.
그를 찾았다고 믿었기에
I did what I did because...
...I believe that search is over.
내 할 일을 한 거야
Get some rest.
푹 쉬어
휴식이 필요할 거야
You're going to need it.
For what?
뭘 위해서요?
Your training.
훈련을 위해서
안녕, 잘 잤어?
Morning. Did you sleep?
오늘 밤엔
You will tonight.
잠이 잘 올 거야
I guarantee it.
I'm Tank. I'll be your operator.
난 탱크야
내가 널 조작할 거야
- 넌 구멍이...
- 그래, 없어
- You don't have any--
- Holes? Nope.
나와 도저 형은
100% 구식 방법으로
Me and my brother, Dozer, are 100%
pure, old-fashioned, homegrown human.
생겨난 인간들이야
진짜 세상에서
Born free right here...
...in the real world.
자유롭게 태어난
Genuine child of Zion.
시온의 자녀거든
- Zion?
- If the war was over tomorrow...
- 시온?
- 만약 전쟁이 끝난다면
- 파티가 열릴 곳이지
- 도시야?
...Zion's where the party would be.
It's a city?
마지막 남은 인간의 도시지
The last human city.
The only place we have left.
어디 있는데?
Where is it?
땅 속에, 아직 따뜻한
지구의 중심부 가까이 있어
Deep underground near the Earth's core,
where it's still warm.
오래 살면 갈 수도 있겠지
You live long enough,
you might see it.
젠장! 네 능력을
정말 보고 싶어
Goddamn! I gotta tell you, I'm excited
to see what you're capable of...
...if Morpheus is right and all.
모피어스가 맞다면 말이지
이런 얘길 하면 안 되지만
We're not supposed to
talk about this, but...
네가 맞다면...
...if you are...
정말 신나는 거지
...it's a very exciting time.
We got a lot to do.
We gotta get to it.
우린 할 일이 많아
자...
원래는 운영 프로그램으로
시작해야 하는데
We're supposed to start
with these programs first.
그건 지루한 거니까
재미있는 걸로 하자구
That's major boring shit.
Let's do something more fun.
그럼
How about...
...combat training?
전투 훈련을 할까?
유술?
"Jujitsu"?
I'm going to learn jujitsu?
유술을 배우라고?
맙소사!
Holy shit!
"Hey, Mikey, I think he likes it."
맛이 괜찮은가 보지?
How about some more?
더 줄까?
그래...
Hell, yes.
Hell, yeah.
그래
'권법, 태권도, 취권'
How is he?
- 잘 돼 가?
- 10시간째예요, 마치 기계 같아요
Ten hours straight.
He's a machine.
I know kung fu.
쿵푸를 할 줄 알아요
Show me.
보여줘 봐
This is a sparring program...
이건 스파링 프로그램이지
매트릭스 프로그램의
현실과 비슷해
...similar to the programmed reality
of the Matrix.
기본 규칙은 같아
중력도 있고
It has the same basic rules.
Like gravity.
이 규칙들은 컴퓨터
시스템과 같은 거야
These rules are no different
than those of a computer system.
몇몇은 우회할 수도 있고
Some of them can be bent.
Others can be broken.
몇몇은 깨뜨릴 수도 있지
Understand?
알겠나?
Then hit me...
그럼 공격해 봐,
할 수 있으면
...if you can.
Good!
좋아!
적응력, 순발력 다...
Adaptation.
Improvisation.
하지만 문제는
But your weakness...
기술이 아냐
...is not your technique.
모피어스가 네오와 싸워요
Morpheus is fighting Neo.
내가 어떻게 이겼지?
How did I beat you?
너무 빨라서요
You're too fast.
내가 빠르거나
Do you believe that...
힘이 센 게
...my being stronger or faster...
내 근육 탓일까? 여기서?
...has anything to do
with my muscles in this place?
네가 공기를 마신다고 생각해?
You think you're breathing air?
다시 해!
Again!
정말 빠르다!
Jesus Christ, he's fast!
신경 운동이 엄청 빨라요
His neuro-kinetics
are way above normal.
What are you waiting for?
뭘 기다려?
넌 이것보단 빠르잖아
You're faster than this.
Don't think you are.
생각하지 말고
Know you are.
인식을 해
Come on! Stop trying to hit me,
and hit me!
때리려고만 하지 말고
진짜로 때려!
I don't believe it.
믿을 수가 없어
I know what you're trying to do.
뭘 하려는 건지 알아요
네 마음을 풀어주려는 거야
I'm trying to free your mind, Neo.
문까지만 안내할 수 있지
나가는 건 직접 해야 돼
But I can only show you the door.
You have to walk through it.
탱크, 점프 프로그램을 로드해
Tank, load the jump program.
'로드'
You have to let it all go, Neo.
Fear...
모든 걸 버려, 네오
두려움...
의심, 불신까지
...doubt and disbelief.
Free your mind.
마음을 자유롭게 해 줘
Whoa.
알았어
Okey-dokey.
마음을 연다
Free my mind.
What if he makes it?
- 성공하면 어떻게 되죠?
- 첫 시도에 성공한 적은 없어
- No one's ever made their first jump.
- I know.
알아요, 알아
- 만약 성공한다면요
- 못 할 거야
- But what if he does?
- He won't.
Come on.
힘내
All right.
좋아
문제없어, 마음을 연다
No problem. Free my mind.
Free my mind. No problem. Right.
마음을 열자
문제없다구, 그래
이게 무슨 뜻이죠?
What does that mean?
아무 뜻도 없어
It doesn't mean anything.
Everybody falls the first time.
누구나 처음엔 떨어져
안 그래, 트리니티?
Right, Trin?
- 진짜가 아니라더니
- 생각이 진짜로 만들지
- I thought it wasn't real.
- Your mind makes it real.
매트릭스에서 죽으면
If you're killed in the Matrix...
...you die here?
- 여기서도 죽나요?
- 정신이 죽으면 몸도 죽어
The body cannot live without the mind.
I don't remember you ever
bringing me dinner.
나한테는 한 번도
안 갖다 주더니
그가 특별하긴 하지?
There is something about him,
isn't there?
이제 와서 믿는다구?
You're a believer now?
I keep wondering...
네오를 '그'라고 믿는다면
...if Morpheus is so sure,
why not take him to see the Oracle?
왜 오라클한테 안 데려가?
준비가 되면 가겠지
Morpheus will take him
when he's ready.
매트릭스는 시스템이야
The Matrix is a system, Neo.
그 시스템이 우리의 적이다
That system is our enemy.
But when you're inside,
what do you see?
둘러보면 뭐가 보이나?
사업가, 교사, 변호사, 목수
Businessmen, teachers,
lawyers, carpenters.
우리가 구하려는
사람들의 마음이지
The very minds of the people
we are trying to save.
하지만 그때까진
이들도 시스템의 일부니까
But until we do, these people are
a part of that system...
...and that makes them our enemy.
우리의 적이지
You have to understand...
이들 대부분은 아직
떠날 준비가 안 돼 있어
...most of these people are not
ready to be unplugged.
그들은 너무나도
And many of them are so inert...
시스템에 잘 길들여져서
...so hopelessly dependent
on the system...
시스템을 보호하려고 하지
...that they will fight to protect it.
내 말을 듣고 있나? 아니면
빨간 옷 입은 여자를 봤나?
Were you listening to me or looking
at the woman in the red dress?
- I was--
- Look again.
- 전...
- 다시 봐
멈춰
Freeze it.
- 매트릭스가 아녜요?
- 그래
- This isn't the Matrix?
- No.
자네한테 한 가지만을
가르치기 위한 프로그램이지
It's another training program
designed to teach you one thing:
If you are not one of us,
you are one of them.
자네가 우리 편이 아니면
요원이란 거야
- What are they?
- Sentient programs.
- 그들은 뭐죠?
- 지각 있는 프로그램이지
시스템에 연결된
어떤 프로그램이든 침입한다
They can move in and out of any
software still hardwired to their system.
That means that anyone
we haven't unplugged...
그 얘기는 곧
우리가 못 구한 누구든지
요원일 수 있다는 거지
...is potentially an agent.
Inside the Matrix...
매트릭스 안에서는
...they are everyone...
누구나...
요원일 수 있어
...and they are no one.
우린 그들로부터
도망치면서 살아남았지
We have survived by hiding
and running from them...
하지만 그들은 문지기야
...but they are the gatekeepers.
They're guarding all the doors
and holding all the keys.
그들이 문을 지키고
열쇠를 쥐고 있다
그러니까 누군가가
그들과 싸워야 한다는 거지
Sooner or later, someone will
have to fight them.
Someone?
누군가?
거짓말은 안 하겠다
I won't lie to you, Neo.
그들과 싸웠던 자들 중에
Every single man or woman who
has fought an agent, has died.
살아남은 자는 아직 없어
But where they have failed,
you will succeed.
하지만 자넨 성공할 거야
Why?
왜죠?
요원은 콘크리트 벽을
부술 수도 있고
I've seen an agent punch
through a concrete wall.
총알을 퍼부어대도
우습게 피하지만
Men have emptied entire clips at them
and hit nothing but air.
그들의 힘과 스피드는
매트릭스 안에서 제한되지
Yet their strength and speed are still
based in a world built on rules.
그렇기 때문에
Because of that...
절대로 너를 능가할 순 없어
...they will never be as strong
or as fast as you can be.
그럼 나도 총알을
What are you telling me?
피할 수 있다고요?
That I can dodge bullets?
아니, 네오
No, Neo.
네가 준비가 돼 있다면
I'm trying to tell you
that when you're ready...
그럴 필요도 없어
...you won't have to.
We got trouble.
문제가 생겼어요
- 시온에서 경고했나?
- 다른 반란선 에서요
- Did Zion send the warning?
- No, another ship.
젠장
Shit.
스퀴디가 빠르게 접근해요!
- Squiddy's sweeping in quick.
- Squiddy?
- '스퀴디'?
- 센티넬
A sentinel. A killing machine
designed for one thing.
살인기계야
적을 찾아 파괴하지
Search and destroy.
저쪽에 착륙시켜
Set her down there.
How are we doing, Tank?
상황이 어때?
전원 차단
Power off-line.
EMP 준비
EMP armed...
- ...and ready.
- EMP?
- 완료
Electromagnetic pulse.
전자기 펄스야
사정권 내에서 적의
전기 시스템을 파괴하지
Disables any electrical system
in the blast radius.
It's the only weapon we have
against the machines.
우리의 유일한 무기야
- Where are we?
- Their old service and waste systems.
- 여긴 어디지?
- 그들의 옛 폐기 시스템이지
Sewers.
- 하수도군
- 원래는 거대한
There used to be cities
that spanned hundreds of miles.
도시들이 있었는데
지금은 하수도만 남았어
Now these sewers are
all that's left.
조용히 해!
Quiet.
Whoa! Neo.
깜짝 놀랐잖아
You scared the bejesus out of me.
- 미안해요
- 괜찮아
- Sorry.
- It's okay.
Is that...?
- 저게...
- 매트릭스냐고?
The Matrix?
Yeah.
그래
- 암호화된 걸 봐야 해요?
- 물론이지
- Do you always look at it encoded?
- Well, you have to.
컨스트럭트를 위한
이미지 변환기가 있거든
The image translators work
for the construct program.
But there's way too much information
to decode the Matrix.
하지만 해독해야 할
정보가 너무 많아
익숙해지면 코드는 안 보이고
You get used to it.
I don't even see the code.
온갖 여자들만 보이지
All I see is blonde, brunette, redhead.
좀...
Do you...
- 마실래?
- 좋아요
...want a drink?
Sure.
You know...
자네가
뭘 생각하는지 알아
...I know what you're thinking.
나도 같은 생각이니까
Because right now I'm thinking
the same thing.
Actually, I've been thinking it
ever since I got here.
난 항상 그 생각뿐이지
Why, oh, why didn't I take
the blue pill?
'파란 약을 먹을걸...'
괜찮지?
Good shit, huh?
도저가 만들어
Dozer makes it.
엔진을 청소하고
뇌세포를 죽이는 데 쓰지
It's good for two things:
Degreasing engines and
killing brain cells.
So can I ask you something?
하나 물어 봐도 돼?
Did he tell you why he did it?
그가 얘길 했어?
왜 데려왔는지?
Why you're here?
Jesus!
맙소사!
얼마나 부담스러워?
What a mind job.
세상을 구해야 한다니
So you're here to save the world.
What do you say
to something like that?
기분이 어떠냐구?
충고 한마디 하지
A little piece of advice.
You see an agent...
요원을 보면
...you do what we do:
우리처럼 해
뛰어
Run.
You run your ass off.
죽어라고 뛰어
Thanks for the drink.
술 고마웠어요
좋은 꿈 꿔
Sweet dreams.
합의가 된 건가, 레이건?
Do we have a deal, Mr. Reagan?
있죠
You know...
...I know this steak doesn't exist.
이게 진짜가
아니란 걸 알아요
I know that when I put it
in my mouth...
입에 넣으면
매트릭스가 내 두뇌에
...the Matrix is telling my brain
that it is...
맛있다는
...juicy...
신호를 보내 주죠
...and delicious.
내가 9년 만에
After nine years...
뭘 깨달았는지 알아요?
...you know what I realize?
'모르는 게 약이다'
Ignorance is bliss.
그럼 된 거군
Then we have a deal.
I don't want to remember nothing.
난 아무것도
기억하고 싶지 않아요
Nothing. You understand?
아무것도! 알았죠?
And I want to be rich.
그리고 부자에다가
유명해지고 싶소
You know, someone important.
배우 처럼요
Like an actor.
원하시는 대로, 레이건
Whatever you want, Mr. Reagan.
Okay.
좋아요
내 몸을 다시
발전소에 데려가서
You get my body
back in a power plant...
매트릭스에 꽂아 주면
원하는 걸 주겠소
...reinsert me into the Matrix...
...I'll get you what you want.
Access codes to the Zion mainframe.
시온의 메인프레임 접근 코드
그건 모른다고 했잖아요
No. I told you, I don't know them.
아는 사람을 데려오죠
I can get you the man who does.
모피어스
Morpheus.
Here you go, buddy.
Breakfast of champions.
여기 있네, 친구
최고의 아침식사
눈 감고 먹으면
날계란을 먹는 기분이죠
Close your eyes, it feels
like you're eating runny eggs.
Or a bowl of snot.
아니면 콧물이나
사실 무슨 맛이냐면...
You know what it reminds me of?
'테이스티 휘트' 같아요
먹어 봤어요?
Tastee Wheat. Did you
ever eat Tastee Wheat?
너도 실제로 먹은 적은 없지
No, but technically,
neither did you.
내 말이 그 말이에요
That's exactly my point. Exactly.
그런데 기계들은
Because you have to wonder...
어떻게 그 맛을 아냐
이 말이죠
...how do the machines really know
what Tastee Wheat tasted like?
Maybe they got it wrong.
잘못 알았을 수도 있죠
내가 알고 있는 그 맛이
실제로는
Maybe what I think Tastee Wheat
tasted like, actually tasted like...
...oatmeal or tuna fish.
오트밀이나
참치 맛일 수도 있죠
That makes you wonder.
Take chicken, for example.
그런 의미에서
닭고기를 예로 들면
닭고기 맛을
어떻게 만들지 몰라서
Maybe they didn't know
what to make it taste like...
...which is why it tastes
like everything.
다 비슷하게
만든 건지도 모르죠
- And maybe they--
- Shut up.
- 그리고 또...
- 닥쳐, 마우스
단세포 단백질과
It's a single-celled protein...
합성 아미노산
비타민, 미네랄의 집합이야
...combined with synthetic aminos,
vitamins and minerals.
몸에 필요한 건 다 있어
Everything the body needs.
전부 다 있는 건 아녜요
It doesn't have everything
the body needs.
I understand you've run through
the agent training program.
요원 훈련 프로그램에
들어가 봤죠?
You know, I wrote that program.
그거 내가 만들었어요
또 시작이군
Here it comes.
- What did you think of her?
- Of who?
- 그 여자 어땠어요?
- 누구?
The woman in the red dress.
I designed her.
빨간 드레스 여자요
내가 디자인했죠
별로 말수는 없지만
She doesn't talk very much...
만나고 싶다면...
자리를 마련해 줄게요
...but if you'd like to meet her,
I can arrange a more personal milieu.
- 디지털 포주가 나셨군
- 위선자들의 말은 무시해요
The digital pimp hard at work.
Pay no attention to
these hypocrites, Neo.
To deny our own impulses...
충동 본능을 무시하면
...is to deny the very thing
that makes us human.
인간이길 무시하는 거죠
도저, 식사가 끝나면
송신 단계로 상승시켜
Dozer, when you're done...
...bring the ship up to broadcast depth.
네오를
We're going in.
그녀에게 데려간다
I'm taking Neo to see her.
See who?
누구요?
The Oracle.
오라클
모두 주목 바랍니다
Everyone please observe...
안전벨트와
금연 표시등이 켜졌습니다
...the "fasten seat belt"
and "no smoking" signs are on.
Sit back and enjoy your flight.
편하게 앉아 즐기십시오
들어왔다
We're in.
한 시간 후에 돌아온다
We'll be back in an hour.
Unbelievable...
믿어지지 않지?
안 그래?
...isn't it?
- 이런!
- 왜?
- God!
- What?
내 단골집이야
I used to eat there.
국수를 잘 했었지
Really good noodles.
I have these memories from my life.
내가 기억하는 모든 게...
전부 가짜였다니
None of them happened.
What does that mean?
그게 무슨 의미지?
매트릭스는 네가 누군지
말해줄 수 없어
That the Matrix cannot tell you
who you are.
But an oracle can?
- 오라클은 괜찮고?
- 그건 얘기가 달라
That's different.
Did you go to her?
그녀한테 가 봤어?
그래
Yes.
What did she tell you?
뭐라고 말했어?
그녀는...
She told me...
뭐?
What?
다 왔다
We're here.
네오, 날 따라와
Neo, come with me.
이 오라클이 예언을 했다는
So is this the same oracle
that made...
...the prophecy?
- 그 예언자인가요?
- 그래
Yes. She's very old. She's been
with us since the beginning.
나이가 많지
처음부터 함께 했으니까
- 처음?
- 저항 운동
- The beginning?
- Of the Resistance.
And she knows what? Everything?
그녀가 모든 걸 알아요?
충분히 안다고 하실 거야
She would say she knows enough.
And she's never wrong.
틀린 적도 없구요?
이건 틀리고 맞고의
문제가 아냐
Try not to think of it
in terms of right and wrong.
She is a guide, Neo.
그녀는 길을
안내하는 역할을 하는 거지
She can help you to find the path.
She helped you?
- 당신도 도와줬어요?
- 그래
Yes.
그녀가 뭐라고 했어요?
What did she tell you?
That I would find the One.
'그'를 찾을 거라고
I told you I can only
show you the door.
문까지만 안내할 수 있어
직접 들어가야 해
You have to walk through it.
안녕, 네오
제때 왔군
Hello, Neo.
You're right on time.
편하게 있어요, 모피어스
네오, 따라와요
Make yourself at home, Morpheus.
Neo, come with me.
'그'의 다른 후보들이죠
These are the other Potentials.
기다려요
You can wait here.
휘게 하려고 생각하진 말아요
Do not try and bend the spoon.
That's impossible.
그건 불가능해요
그 대신에 진실만을 인식해요
Instead, only try
to realize the truth.
What truth?
무슨 진실?
숟가락이 없다는 진실
There is no spoon.
숟가락이 없다고?
There is no spoon?
그러면 숟가락이 아닌
나 자신이 휘는 거죠
Then you'll see that it is not the spoon
that bends. It is only yourself.
오라클님이 오시래요
The Oracle will you see now.
네가 네오구나
I know you're Neo.
잠깐만 기다려라
Be right with you.
- 오라클님이세요?
- 딩동댕!
- You're the Oracle?
- Bingo.
예상하고 많이 다르지?
Not quite what you
were expecting, right?
거의 다 됐어
Almost done.
냄새가 참 좋지?
Smell good, don't they?
Yeah.
- 네
- 앉으라고 하고 싶지만
I'd ask you to sit down...
앉지도 않을 거고...
...but you're not going to anyway.
- 꽃병은 신경 쓰지 마
- 꽃병요?
- And don't worry about the vase.
- What vase?
그 꽃병
That vase.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
신경 쓰지 말라니까
I said, don't worry about it.
애들더러 고치라고 할게
I'll get one of my kids to fix it.
어떻게 알았죠?
How did you know?
네가 정말로 궁금해 할 건...
What's really going to bake
your noodle later on is...
'내가 말을 안 했어도
꽃병을 깼을까?'란 거겠지
...would you still have broken it
if I hadn't said anything?
생각보다 귀엽구나
You're cuter than I thought.
그녀가 좋아할 만해
I can see why she likes you.
- 누가요?
- 똑똑하진 않구나
Who?
Not too bright, though.
왜 나한테 왔는지는 알지?
You know why Morpheus
brought you to see me.
그래서...
So...
어떻게 생각해?
...what do you think?
자신이 '그'라고 생각해?
Do you think you are the One?
솔직히 모르겠어요
I don't know.
저게 무슨 뜻인지 알아?
You know what that means?
라틴어다
It's Latin.
'너 자신을 알라'
Means, "Know thyself."
한 가지 비밀을 알려 주지
I'll let you in on a little secret.
자신이 '그'란 사실은
사랑에 빠지는 것과 같아
Being the One is just
like being in love.
아무도 말해줄 수 없고
자신이 스스로 알지
No one can tell you you're in love.
You just know it...
온몸으로
...through and through.
아는 거지
Balls to bones.
Well...
그럼...
어디 한번 볼까?
...I'd better have a look at you.
입을 벌리고 '아' 해봐
Open your mouth. Say, "Ah."
좋아
Okay...
이제 내가 '흥미롭군,
하지만...'이라고 말해야겠지
Now I'm supposed to say,
"Hmm, that's interesting, but..."
그럼 자네가 할 말은...
Then you say:
'하지만 뭐요'?
But what?
하지만 자넨 이미
내가 할 말을 알고 있어
But you already know
what I'm going to tell you.
- 전 '그'가 아니군요
- 미안하다
- I'm not the One.
- Sorry, kid.
넌 재능이 있지만
You got the gift...
...but it looks like
you're waiting for something.
뭔가를 기다리고
있는 것 같아
What?
- 뭘요?
- 다음 인생, 누가 알겠어?
Your next life, maybe. Who knows?
다 그런 법이야
That's the way these things go.
- 뭐가 웃기지?
- 모피어스한테...
- What's funny?
- Morpheus.
거의 설득됐었거든요
He almost had me convinced.
알아
I know.
불쌍한 모피어스...
Poor Morpheus.
그가 없으면 우린 안 돼
Without him, we're lost.
'그가 없으면'이라뇨?
What do you mean, "without him"?
정말 알고 싶나?
Are you sure you want
to hear this?
모피어스는 널 믿어, 네오
Morpheus believes in you, Neo.
너도 나도 아무도
And no one, not you, not even me...
그를 설득할 순 없어
...can convince him otherwise.
널 구하기 위해
He believes it so blindly...
목숨을 버릴 만큼
그는 눈이 멀었어
...that he's going to sacrifice
his life to save yours.
- 네?
- 넌 선택을 해야 돼
What?
You're going to
have to make a choice.
모피어스의 목숨과
In the one hand,
you'll have Morpheus' life.
네 목숨 중에서 말이야
And in the other hand,
you'll have your own.
둘 중 하나는 죽는다
One of you is going to die.
누가 죽을지는
네 손에 달렸어
Which one will be up to you.
정말로 미안하다
I'm sorry, kiddo. I really am.
넌 심성이 착해
You have a good soul.
나도 나쁜 소식은
전하기 싫어
And I hate giving
good people bad news.
하지만 걱정 마
Don't worry about it.
저 문을 나가는 순간
As soon as you
step outside that door...
기분이 좋아지기
시작할 테니까
...you'll start feeling better.
이 엉터리 같은 일은
다 잊게 될 거야
You'll remember you don't believe
in any of this fate crap.
네 삶은 네가
통제하는 거니까
You're in control of your own life.
기억하지?
Remember?
Here...
여기...
과자를 하나 먹어
...take a cookie.
과자를 다 먹고 나면
I promise, by the time
you're done eating it...
기분이 좋아질 거야
...you'll feel right as rain.
네가 들은 건...
What was said...
너만...
...was for you...
알고 있으면 돼
...and for you alone.
'빨간 드레스의 여자'
돌아오고 있다
They're on the way.
뭐지?
What is that?
와, '데자부'네
Oh, déjà vu.
- 뭐라고 했어?
- 그냥 본 걸 또 봤다구
What did you just say?
Nothing.
Just déjà vu.
- 뭘 봤는데?
- 어떻게 된 거야?
- What did you see?
- What happened?
검은 고양이가 지나갔는데
A black cat went past us...
똑같은 게 또 지나갔어
...then another just like it.
완전히 똑같았어?
Was it the same cat?
- I'm not sure.
- Switch, Apoc.
그랬을지도 몰라
스위치, 에이팍
What is it?
- 뭐야?
- '기시감'은 매트릭스의 결함이야
A déjà vu is usually a glitch in the
Matrix when they change something.
무슨 변화가
생길 때 나타나지
Oh, my God.
맙소사
Let's go.
가자!
선을 끊었어! 함정이야!
They cut the hard line.
It's a trap! Get out!
Oh, no.
이런...
이게 변한 거군
우린 완전히 갇혔어
- That's what they changed.
- We're trapped.
진정해, 전화 줘
Be calm. Give me your phone.
추적될 텐데요
They'll be able to track it.
어쩔 수 없어
We have no choice.
- 교환
- 탱크?
Operator.
탱크, 빨리 이 건물의
설계도를 찾아
Find a structural drawing of
this building. Find it fast.
- 찾았어요
- 수도관 벽을 찾아
- Got it!
- I need the main wet-wall.
Eighth floor.
8층이다
8층에 있다!
They're on the eighth floor.
스위치, 똑바로 가
Switch, straight ahead.
Neo...
네가 '그'이길 바래
I hope the Oracle
gave you some good news.
거기서 왼쪽이에요
Now left. That's it.
좋아
Good.
어디로 갔지?
Where are they?
벽 안에 있습니다
They're in the walls.
벽 안이다!
In the walls!
요원이다!
It's an agent!
Morpheus!
You must get Neo out!
네오를 데리고 가!
반드시 살려야 해!
He's all that matters!
안 돼요, 모피어스!
- No, Morpheus! Don't!
- Trinity, go!
트리니티, 빨리!
가!
Go!
- 두고 갈 순 없어!
- 가야 해!
- We can't leave him!
- We have to!
사이퍼! 빨리 와!
Cypher, come on!
위대한 모피어스
The great Morpheus.
We meet at last.
드디어 나타났군
넌 누구지?
And you are?
스미스
A Smith.
스미스 요원이다
Agent Smith.
내게 너희는 다 똑같아
You all look the same to me.
데려가
Take him.
안 돼!
No!
- 교환
- 출구가 필요해
- Operator.
- I need an exit, fast.
- 사이퍼?
- 그래
빌어먹을 사고가 났어
차 사고야
There was an accident.
Goddamn car accident.
갑자기 쾅 하고
All of a sudden, boom.
- 그래도 천운이 돌봤나 봐
- 됐어
Somebody up there still likes me.
I got you.
- 빨리 데려가 줘
- 프랭클린가와 에리가의
Just get me out of here fast.
Nearest exit, Franklin and Erie.
An old TV repair shop.
전파상으로 가
알았어
Right.
- 교환
- 탱크, 나야
- Operator.
- Tank, it's me.
모피어스는 살았어?
Is Morpheus alive?
Is Morpheus alive, Tank?
놈들이 어디론가 옮기고 있어
Yes. They're moving him.
I don't know where.
- 살아있어, 출구가 필요해
- 사이퍼가 근처에 있어
He's alive. We need an exit.
You're not far from Cypher.
- 사이퍼?
- 그래
- Cypher?
- I know.
- 프랭클린가와 에리가에
- 알았어
- I sent him to Franklin and Erie.
- Got it.
왔어
Got him.
- 어디 있어?
- 전화 쪽으로 오고 있어
Where are they?
Making the call.
잘 됐군
Good.
You first.
먼저 받아
젠장!
Shit!
Tank!
No!
그냥 끊어졌어
I don't know. It just went dead.
안녕, 트리니티
Hello, Trinity.
사이퍼? 탱크는 어디 있어?
Cypher? Where's Tank?
난...
You know...
오래 전부터...
...for a long time...
널 사랑한다고 생각했어
...I thought I was in love with you.
네 꿈을 꾸곤 했지
I used to dream about you.
넌 아름다운 여자야, 트리니티
You're a beautiful woman, Trinity.
일이 이렇게 돼서 유감이야
Too bad things had to
turn out this way.
You killed them.
네가 죽였구나
- What?
- Oh, God.
- 뭐?
- 맙소사
난 지쳤어, 트리니티
I'm tired, Trinity.
전쟁도...
I'm tired of this war...
싸우는 것도 지겨워
여기도 지긋지긋하고
...tired of fighting.
I'm tired of this ship...
추운 것도, 매일 똑같은
죽을 먹는 것도 말이야
...of being cold, of eating
the same goddamn goop every day.
But most of all...
하지만 무엇보다도
모피어스 놈이 지겨워
...I'm tired of that jackoff
and all of his bullshit.
놀랬지, 이놈아?
Surprise, asshole!
이렇게 될 줄은
I bet you never saw this coming...
몰랐지?
...did you?
네놈이 뒈지는 광경을
God, I wish I could be there...
봐야 하는데
...when they break you.
네놈이 죽기 직전에 가서
I wish I could walk in
just when it happens...
내가 배신했다는 걸
...so right then...
보여 주는 건데
...you'd know it was me.
You gave them Morpheus.
- 네가 모피어스를 넘겼군
- 놈은 우릴 속였어
He lied to us, Trinity.
속였다구!
He tricked us!
네가 사실대로 말했으면
If you had told us the truth...
빨간 약은 안 먹었잖아!
...we would've told you to shove
that red pill up your ass!
그는 우리에게 자유를 줬어
That is not true, Cypher.
He set us free.
자유?
이게 자유야?
"Free." You call this free?
날 부려먹기만 했어
All I do is what he tells me to do.
그렇게 사느니 차라리
If I had to choose between
that and the Matrix...
매트릭스를 선택하겠어
...I choose the Matrix.
매트릭스는 가짜야
The Matrix isn't real.
그렇지 않아
I disagree, Trinity.
난 매트릭스가 이 세상보다
I think the Matrix...
더 진짜 같다고 생각해
...can be more real than this world.
여기서 플러그만 뽑으면
All I do is pull the plug here.
넌 에이팍이
But there...
죽는 걸 봐야 되지
...you have to watch Apoc die.
Trinity.
안 돼!
- 진짜 세상 좋아하네
- 하지만 넌 나왔어
- Welcome to the real world.
- But you're out, Cypher.
- 다시 못 돌아가
- 그건 네 생각이지
- You can't go back.
- That's what you think.
내 몸을 다시 넣어 준대
They'll reinsert my body.
다시 잠이 들고
전부 잊어버리는 거지
I go back to sleep. When I wake up,
I won't remember a thing.
그건 그렇고, 스위치한테
할 말이라도 있다면...
By the way...
...if you have anything important
to say to Switch...
- 지금 말해야 될 걸
- 제발 하지 마
...say it now.
- No, please don't.
- Not like this.
이렇게는 싫어
Not like this.
너무 늦었어
Too late.
빌어먹을, 사이퍼!
Goddamn you, Cypher!
날 미워하진 마, 트리니티
Don't hate me, Trinity.
난 말을 전할 뿐이야
I'm just a messenger.
지금 내 말을 증명해 보이지
And right now,
I'm going to prove it to you.
모피어스의 말이 맞다면
If Morpheus was right...
난 플러그를 뽑을 수 없겠지
...there's no way
I can pull this plug.
만약 네오가 '그'라면
If Neo's the One...
그를 죽이려는 나를
...then there'd have to be...
막아줄 기적이 일어날 테니까
...some kind of a miracle to stop me.
Right?
맞지?
죽으면 '그'가 아닌 거지
I mean, how can he be the One...
...if he's dead?
모피어스를 믿는지의
You never did answer me before...
여부를 밝히지 않았지?
...if you bought into
Morpheus' bullshit.
'네, 아니오'로만 대답해
Come on. All I want
is a little yes or no.
그의 눈을 쳐다봐
Look into his eyes...
크고 예쁜 그 눈을...
...those big, pretty eyes...
그리고
...and tell me...
'네' 아니면
...yes...
'아니오'로 대답해 봐
...or no.
- 믿어
- 아냐!
- Yes.
- No!
I don't believe it.
난 안 믿어!
믿든 안 믿든
넌 바비큐가 될 거다!
Believe it or not, you piece of shit,
you're still going to burn!
You first.
먼저 받아
- 다쳤군
- 괜찮아
- You're hurt.
- I'll be all right.
도저는?
Dozer?
이 아름다움과 천재성을
Have you ever stood and stared at it?
보고 감탄해 본 적이
Marveled at its beauty...
있나?
...its genius?
수십억 인간들이
Billions of people...
그냥 아무 생각 없이 살지
...just living out their lives.
태평하게 말이야
Oblivious.
원래 첫 번째 매트릭스는
Did you know that the first Matrix...
완벽한 인간의 세상으로
계획됐다는 사실을 아나?
...was designed to be a perfect
human world where none suffered...
모두 고통 없이
행복하도록 계획됐지
...where everyone would be happy.
그런데 비극이었지
It was a disaster.
프로그램이 받아들여지지
않았고 인간들은 다 죽었어
No one would accept the program.
Entire crops were lost.
어떤 이들은
Some believe that...
완벽한 세계를 프로그램할
여력이 없다고 생각했지
...we lacked the programming language
to describe your perfect world.
하지만 내 생각에는...
But I believe that...
...as a species...
인간들은 슬픔과
고통을 통해서 현실을
...human beings define
their reality through misery...
정의하는 것 같아
...and suffering.
너희 원시적인 두뇌들은
So the perfect world was a dream...
완벽한 세계의 꿈에서
자꾸 깨어나려고 했지
...that your primitive cerebrum
kept trying to wake up from.
그래서 매트릭스가
이렇게 다시 만들어진 거야
Which is why the Matrix was
redesigned to this.
너희 문명의 절정이지
The peak...
...of your civilization.
사실 너희 문명은 아냐
I say, "your civilization"...
우리가 맡은 이후로는
우리의 문명이 됐으니까
...because when we started thinking
for you, it became our civilization...
...which is, of course,
what this is all about.
그래서 이러고 있잖아
진화야, 모피어스
Evolution, Morpheus.
진화라구
Evolution.
공룡처럼 말이야
Like the dinosaur.
창밖을 봐
Look out that window.
너희 때는 지났어
You had your time.
미래는 우리 세상이야
모피어스
The future is our world, Morpheus.
미래는 우리 시대라구
The future is our time.
문제가 있겠는걸
There could be a problem.
- 뭘 하는 거지?
- 머릿속에 침투하는 거야
- What are they doing to him?
- They're breaking into his mind.
해킹과 비슷해
시간문제일 뿐이야
It's like hacking a computer.
All it takes is time.
얼마나 걸리지?
How much time?
정신에 달려 있어
하지만 결국
Depends on the mind.
But eventually, it'll crack...
두뇌의 알파파가
이렇게 바뀌게 되면...
...and his alpha patterns
will change from this to this.
그들이 원하는 건
다 말하게 돼 있어
When it does, he'll tell them
anything they want to know.
뭘 원하는데?
What do they want?
시온의 메인 컴퓨터로
들어가는 코드
The leader of every ship is given
codes to Zion's mainframe computer.
요원들이 시온의
메인프레임에 들어가면
If an agent got the codes
and got into Zion's mainframe...
시온은 끝장이야
그렇게 할 순 없지
...they could destroy us.
We can't let that happen.
트리니티, 시온은 너나 나나
Trinity, Zion's more important than me...
...or you...
모피어스보다 중요해
...or even Morpheus.
- 무슨 방법이 있겠지
- 있어, 플러그를 뽑는 거야
There has to be
something we can do.
There is. We pull the plug.
죽인다고?
You're going to kill him?
모피어스를?
Kill Morpheus?
선택의 여지가 없어
We don't have a choice.
인간을 믿는 게 아니었어
Never send a human
to do a machine's job.
내부협력자가 실패했다면
If the insider has failed...
놈들이 플러그를 뽑을 텐데
...they'll sever the connection
as soon as possible, unless--
다 죽지 않았다면...
They're dead. In either case--
계획대로 하는 수밖에
센티넬들을 보내
We have no choice. Continue as planned.
Deploy the sentinels.
당장
Immediately.
당신은 리더 그 이상이었죠
Morpheus, you were more
than a leader to us.
우리의 아버지였어요
You were a father.
잊지 않을게요
We'll miss you always.
Stop!
잠깐!
어떻게 이럴 수 있어?
I don't believe this is happening.
- 이래야만 해
- 그럴까?
- Neo, this has to be done.
- Does it?
모르겠어
I don't know.
- 이건 우연일 수가 없어
- 무슨 소리야?
- This can't be just coincidence.
- What?
The Oracle.
오라클이 이 일을 예언했었어
She told me this would happen.
내가 선택을 해야 할 거라고
She told me that I would
have to make a choice.
무슨 선택?
What choice?
- What are you doing?
- I'm going in.
- 뭘 하려고?
- 들어갈래
- 그건 안 돼
- 가야 해
- No, you're not.
- I have to.
모피어스는
널 구하기 위해서 잡혔어
Neo, Morpheus sacrificed himself
so that we could get you out.
절대로 가면 안 돼
There is no way
that you're going back in.
모피어스는 날 잘못 알고
그렇게 한 거야
Morpheus did what he did because
he believed I'm something I'm not.
What?
뭐?
난 '그'가 아냐
I'm not the One, Trinity.
- 나도 처음엔 놀랐어
- 그럴 리가 없어
- The Oracle hit me with that too.
- No, you have to be.
미안해, 난 평범해
I'm sorry, I'm not.
I'm just another guy.
그건 사실이 아냐
No, Neo, that's not true.
- 사실일 리 없어
- 왜지?
- It can't be true.
- Why?
이건 미친 짓이야, 놈들은
모피어스를 철통같이 지키고 있어
This is loco. They've got Morpheus
in a military-controlled building.
들어가도 요원들이 있어
세 명이나!
Even if you somehow got inside, those
are agents holding him. Three of them.
나도 그를 살리고 싶지만
이건 자살 행위야
I want Morpheus back too, but
what you're talking about is suicide.
그렇게 보이지만 안 그래
That's what it looks like...
...but it's not.
이유는 설명할 수가 없어
I can't explain to you why it's not.
모피어스는 자신이 믿는 걸
위해 목숨까지 바치려 했어
Morpheus believed something, and
he was ready to give his life for it.
나도 이젠 이해가 돼
그래서 가야만 해
I understand that now.
That's why I have to go.
- 왜?
- 나도 뭔가를 믿으니까
- Why?
- Because I believe in something.
What?
뭘?
그를 살릴 수 있다고 믿어
I believe I can bring him back.
- 뭘 하는 거야?
- 같이 갈 거야
- What are you doing?
- Going with you.
- No, you're not.
- "No"?
- 그건 안 돼
- 안 돼?
내가 뭘 믿는지 알아?
Let me tell you what I believe.
모피어스는 너보다
나한테 의미가 더 커
Morpheus means more to me
than he does to you.
정말 그를 살리고 싶다면
내 도움이 필요할 걸
I believe if you are serious about
saving him, you will need my help.
그리고 이젠
내가 지휘관이니까
And since I am the ranking officer...
내 명령이 싫으면
지옥에나 가
...if you don't like it,
I believe you can go to hell.
달리 갈 데도 없을 테니
Because you aren't going anywhere else.
탱크, 로드해 줘
Tank...
...Ioad us up.
이곳에 있는 동안
깨닫게 된
I'd like to share
a revelation that I've had...
사실이 있어
...during my time here.
네 종족을 분류하다가
It came to me when I tried
to classify your species...
영감을 얻었지
...and I realized...
너희는 포유류가 아니었어
...that you're not actually mammals.
지구상의 모든 포유류들은...
Every mammal on this planet...
본능적으로 자연과
...instinctively develops an equilibrium
with the surrounding environment.
조화를 이루는데
인간들은 안 그래
But you humans do not.
한 지역에서 번식을 하고
You move to an area
and you multiply...
모든 자연 자원을
소모해 버리지
...and multiply until every
natural resource is consumed.
너희의 유일한 생존 방식은
The only way you can survive...
또 다른 장소로 이동하는 거지
...is to spread to another area.
이 지구에는
똑같은 방식을 따르는
There is another organism
on this planet...
유기체가 또 하나 있어
...that follows the same pattern.
Do you know what it is?
그게 뭔지 아나?
바이러스야
A virus.
인간들이란 존재는 질병이야
Human beings are a disease.
지구의 암이지
A cancer of this planet.
너희는 역병이고
You are a plague.
우리가
And we...
치료제다
...are the cure.
뭐가 필요하지?
Okay, so what do you need?
기적?
Besides a miracle.
총이
Guns.
많이 필요해
Lots of guns.
Neo...
이런 일은 아무도
시도한 적이 없어
No one has ever done
anything like this.
그래서 성공할 거야
That's why it's going to work.
왜 약효가 안 나지?
Why isn't the serum working?
질문이 잘못된 게 아닐까?
Perhaps we're asking
the wrong questions.
나가들 있어
Leave me with him.
당장!
Now.
기다려요, 모피어스
Hold on, Morpheus.
그들이 가요, 기다려요
They're coming for you.
They're coming.
들리나, 모피어스?
Can you hear me, Morpheus?
솔직하게...
I'm going to be honest...
말해 주지
...with you.
난...
I...
...hate...
여기가 싫어
...this place...
이 동물원...
...this zoo...
감옥...
...this prison...
현실, 뭐라고 부르든 간에
...this reality,
whatever you want to call it.
더 이상은 못 참아
I can't stand it any longer.
냄새 때문이지
It's the smell.
그런 게 있다면 말이야
If there is such a thing.
냄새가 내게도 배는 것 같아
I feel saturated by it.
네...
I can...
...taste...
지독한 냄새가
느껴져
...your stink.
그럴 때마다 마치
나도 감염된 것 같아
And every time I do, I fear that
I have somehow been infected by it.
It's repulsive.
아주 불쾌해
안 그래?
Isn't it?
난 여기서 벗어나야 해
I must get out of here.
네 머릿속에
I must get free.
내가 나갈 열쇠가 있어
And in this mind is the key.
내 열쇠다
My key.
시온만 파괴되면
난 여기 있을 필요가 없어
Once Zion is destroyed,
there is no need for me to be here.
알겠나?
Do you understand?
코드가 필요해
I need the codes.
시온으로 들어가야 해
I have to get inside Zion...
코드가 뭔지 빨리 말해
...and you have to tell me how.
말하든가
You're going to tell me...
죽든가
...or you're going to die.
열쇠나 잔돈 같은
금속성 물건이
Please remove any metallic items
you're carrying. Keys, loose change.
있으면 빼주세요
맙소사!
Holy shit!
지원을 바란다! 지원!
Backup. Send backup.
Freeze!
꼼짝 마!
What were you doing?
뭘 하고 있었지?
모르고 있어
He doesn't know.
뭘 몰라?
Know what?
'비상 정지'
'작동'
이 자를 구하려나 봐
I think they're trying to save him.
숟가락은 없다
There is no spoon.
찾아서 없애버려!
Find them and destroy them!
공격 받고 있다!
We're under attack!
Trinity!
Help!
도와줘!
역시 인간이군
Only human.
Dodge this.
이걸 피해 봐
- 어떻게 한 거지?
- 뭘?
- How did you do that?
- Do what?
그들처럼 움직였어
그렇게 빠른 건 처음 봐
You moved like they do.
I've never seen anyone move that fast.
아직 멀었어
It wasn't fast enough.
조종할 수 있어?
Can you fly that thing?
Not yet.
아직은 못 하지
- 교환
- B212 헬기의
Operator.
I need a pilot program
for a B-212 helicopter.
조종법이 필요해
서둘러
Hurry.
가자
Let's go.
안 돼!
No.
모피어스, 일어나요, 일어나
Morpheus, get up.
Get up, get up.
안 되겠어!
He's not going to make it.
잡았어요
Got you.
Trinity!
틀림없어
I knew it.
'그'가 맞았어
He's the One.
이젠 믿겠나, 트리니티?
Do you believe it now, Trinity?
Morpheus...
The Oracle.
오라클이
- 내게 말하길...
- 오라클은
- She told me--
- She told you...
네가 들어야 할 말을
한 것뿐이야
...what you needed to hear.
That's all.
네오, 너도 나처럼
곧 알게 될 거야
Sooner or later you'll realize,
just as I did...
갈 길을 아는 것과
...there's a difference
between knowing the path...
길을 걷는 것의 차이를
...and walking the path.
- 교환
- 탱크
- Operator.
- Tank.
- 반가운 목소리군요
- 출구가 필요해
- It's good to hear your voice.
- We need an exit.
스테이트가와 밸보아가의
전철역입니다
Got one ready. Subway station,
State and Balboa.
- 젠장!
- 추적이 완료됐다
- Damn it!
- The trace was completed.
- 위치가 파악됐다
- 센티넬들이 대기 중이다
- We have their position.
- Sentinels are standing by.
공격을 지시해
Order the strike.
아직 못 빠져나갔어
They're not out yet.
먼저 가세요
You first, Morpheus.
네오, 할 말이 있어
Neo, I want to tell you something...
하지만 그 말을 하면
어떤 뜻이 될지 두려워
...but I'm afraid of
what it could mean if I do.
오라클이 내게 한 말은
모두 성취됐어
Everything the Oracle
told me has come true.
이것만 빼고
Everything but this.
But what?
뭐만 빼고?
Neo!
- 어떻게 된 거야!
- 요원이야
- What happened?
- An agent.
- 날 보내 줘!
- 못 해
- Send me back.
- I can't.
앤더슨
Mr. Anderson.
도망 가, 네오
Run, Neo. Run.
- 뭘 하려는 거죠?
- 믿기 시작했어
What is he doing?
He's beginning to believe.
다 쐈군
You're empty.
피차일반이지
So are you.
네가 죽는 꼴을
즐겁게 감상하겠다
I'm going to enjoy watching you die...
앤더슨
...Mr. Anderson.
이러다 죽겠어
Jesus, he's killing him.
저 소리가 들리나, 앤더슨?
You hear that, Mr. Anderson?
피할 수 없는 소리다
That is the sound of inevitability.
네 죽음의 소리지
It is the sound of your death.
잘 가라, 앤더슨
Goodbye, Mr. Anderson.
내 이름은...
My name...
네오다!
...is Neo.
- 어떻게 됐지?
- 갑자기 사라졌어
- What happened?
- I don't know. I lost him.
'접근 경고'
젠장
Oh, shit.
센티넬들이군
Sentinels.
- 시간은요?
- 5, 6분 남았어
- How long?
- Five, maybe six minutes.
EMP를 충전해
Tank, charge the EMP.
- 그가 돌아와야죠
- 알아, 걱정 마
- We can't use that until he's out.
- I know. Don't worry.
돌아올 거야
He's gonna make it.
하이힐로...?
Flat or pumps? No, just--
뭐야? 내 휴대폰이야!
What the shit? That's my phone!
휴대폰 도둑이야!
That guy took my phone!
Got him!
He's on the run.
찾았어요
뛰고 있어요
빨리 날 내보내 줘!
Mr. Wizard, get me out of here!
와바시가와 레이크가에
옛 출구가 있어
I got an old exit.
Wabash and Lake.
젠장
Oh, shit!
좀 도와줘야겠어!
Help! Need a little help!
문!
The door.
왼쪽 문!
The door on your left.
다른 왼쪽!
Your other left!
뒷문!
The back door.
'적색 경보'
이런...
Oh, no.
놈들이 오는군
Here they come.
그는 올 거야
He's going to make it.
골목 끝의 사다리로
올라가면 303호야
The fire escape at the end
of the alley, room 303.
'경고 : 선체 침입'
들어왔어요
They're inside.
서둘러, 네오
Hurry, Neo.
이럴 리가 없어
It can't be.
확인해
Check him.
죽었다
He's gone.
잘 가게, 앤더슨
Goodbye, Mr. Anderson.
Neo...
난 이제 두렵지 않아
I'm not afraid anymore.
오라클은 내가 사랑에
빠지는 남자가 바로...
The Oracle told me...
...I'd fall in love, and that
the man I loved would be the One.
'그'라고 말했었어
그러니까...
So you see...
당신은 죽을 수 없어
...you can't be dead.
난 당신을
You can't be...
사랑하니까
...because I love you.
들려?
You hear me?
사랑해
I love you.
이제 일어나
Now, get up.
No.
안 돼
어떻게...?
How?
'그'니까
He is the One.
Neo!
거기 있는 걸 안다
I know you're out there.
너희를 느낄 수 있다
I can feel you now.
너희가 우리를
I know that you're afraid.
You're afraid of us.
두려워 한다는 걸 안다
변화가 두려운 거야
You're afraid of change.
'시스템 정지'
난 미래를 모른다
I don't know the future.
이것이 어떻게 끝날지
말하러 온 게 아니다
I didn't come here to tell you
how this is going to end.
어떻게 시작할지를
말하러 온 거다
I came here to tell you
how it's going to begin.
난 이제 이 전화를 끊고
I'll hang up this phone.
이들에게 너희가 보이길
원치 않는 것을 보여 주겠다
And then I'll show these people
what you don't want them to see.
너희가 없는 진짜 세계를
I'm going to show them a world...
보여 주겠다
...without you.
규칙이나 통제,
경계나 국경이 없는 세계
A world without rules and controls,
without borders or boundaries.
모든 것이 가능한 세계를
A world where anything is possible.
그 다음에 어떻게 할지는
Where we go from there...
알아서 하라구
...is a choice I leave to you.